Guide to the Herbert C. (Herbert Coffin) Jones Papers, 1903-1954
Department of Special Collections
- Addendum
  - Bromley Spoils System bill, 1923. (Box 98, Folder 696)
  - California Building and Loan, 1925. (Box 98, Folder 697)
  - Child Labor, 1925.Senate bill #124. (Box 98, Folder 698)
  - Community property. 1920Act. (Box 98, Folder 699)
  - Community property. 1923Act. Senate bill #228. (Box 98, Folder 700)
  - Initiative and Referendum, 1926-7. (Box 99, Folder 701)
  - Jones, Louise C. (Mother) about death of. (Box 99, Folder 702)
  - Judicial Salaries, 1921-22. (Box 99, Folder 703)
  - Judiciary Committee Minutes, 1921 and 1923. (Box 99, Folder 704)
  - Judiciary Committee. Investigation by special committee... of the expenditures of sums of money by persons, firms or corporations interested in propositions voted for at the election held November 7, 1922.Parts 1-5. (Box 99, Folder 705)
  - Parts 6-9 (Box 99, Folder 706)
  - Parts 10-13 (Box 100, Folder 707)
  - Supporting documents. I (Box 100, Folder 708)
  - Supporting Documents. II (Box 100, Folder 709)
  - Lawyer's Bills Assembly 148 and 1242, Senate 21 and 602, 1921. (Box 100, Folder 710)
  - Mooney Case (Box 100, Folder 711)
  - Motor Carriers, 1923-24. (Box 100, Folder 712)
  - Narcotics, 1927. (Box 101, Folder 713)
  - Cuthbert L. Olson, 1938. (Box 101, Folder 714)
  - Owen's Valley Power and Reclamation, 1924-25.I (Box 101, Folder 715)
  - Owen's Valley Power and Reclamation, 1924-25.II (Box 101, Folder 716)
  - Parks, 1928. (Box 101, Folder 717)
  - Personal and family letters (Box 101, Folder 718)
  - Personal and family photographs (Box 101, Folder 719)
  - Political campaigns, 1920, 1922, 1923. (Box 101, Folder 720)
  - Political campaigns, 1924. (Box 101, Folder 721)
  - Political campaigns, 1924Johnson for President (Box 102, Folder 722)
  - Political campaigns, 1925-26Lineberger, Walter F. for U.S. Senate. (Box 102, Folder 723)
  - Political campaigns, 1926Lt. Governor and Race Track. (Box 102, Folder 724)
  - Political campaigns, 1926Jones election. (Box 102, Folder 725)
  - Political campaigns, 1928Presidential. (Box 102, Folder 726)
  - Progressive Voters League, 1923-26. (Box 102, Folder 727)
  - Prohibition, 1924-27. (Box 102, Folder 728)
  - Prohibition, printed matter. (Box 103, Folder 729)
  - Public Health, 1923. (Box 103, Folder 730)
  - Roosevelt Club, 1922. (Box 103, Folder 731)
  - Rosecrucians, judicial proceedings, 1923-31. (Box 103, Folder 732)
  - Rosecrucians, correspondence 1927-33. (Box 103, Folder 733)
  - Rosecrucians. Amorc College lectures and other Rosecrucian printed matter. (Box 103, Folder 734)
  - Senate special investigating committee, 1933. (Box 104, Folder 735)
  - Report on labor legislation and labor record, members of 1913, 1917, 1919, 1921, 1923, 1925, 1931legislatures. (Box 104, Folder 736)
  - Correspondence. Out, 1919-24. (Box 104, Folder 737)
  - Correspondence. Out, 1925-39 (Box 104, Folder 738)
  - Correspondence. Hichborn, F. Letters to and by, 1920-24. (Box 104, Folder 739)
  - Correspondence. Hichborn, F. Letters to and by, 1925. (Box 104, Folder 740)
  - Correspondence. Hichborn, F. Letters to and by, 1926. (Box 104, Folder 741)
  - Correspondence. Hichborn, F. Letters to and by, 1927-46. (Box 105, Folder 742)
  - Hichborn, F. Clippings and miscellany. (Box 105, Folder 743)
  - Correspondence. In, 1913-22. (Box 105, Folder 744)
  - Correspondence. In, 1923. (Box 105, Folder 745)
  - Correspondence. In, 1924. (Box 105, Folder 746)
  - Correspondence. In, 1925. (Box 105, Folder 747)
  - Correspondence. In, 1926. (Box 105, Folder 748)
  - Correspondence. In, 1927-46. (Box 105, Folder 749)
    The correspondence pertains to the subjects filed in the previous folders (692-736).
Subject Index to H.C. Jones Reference Material
Papers is filed chronologically and then alphabetically by subject, thus related subjects can and do appear in five or more years. This index is designed to assist the searcher in locating subject matter without the necessity of reading the entire Register. Numbers correspond to folders in the collection. After obtaining the desired numbers, it is advisable to check the major portion of the Register for fuller details.
accountants - 353
adoption - 459, 504
adult education - 459, 593-597, 692
advisory boards - 216
Agnew State Hospital - 79, 112
agriculture, dept. of - 79, 162, 188, 216, 353, 505
aircraft - 262
alien teachers - 79
All-American Canal - 695
almshouse - 112
Americanism - 162
anatomy bill - 353
animal trainers bill - 314
Anti-Saloon League (under A, correspondence files 1920's) See also Briggs, A.H.
apples - 162
apprentices - 79
arbitration - 216, 354
architects - 79
assessors - 262
automobiles (includes Jitney) - 79, 84, 119, 216, 354
automobiles (includes Jitney) liens - 354
automobiles (includes Jitney) stealing of - 162
aviation - 354
Bank of Italy - 382
banks and banking - 163, 263, 355, 397, 460, 506
Bar Association - 163, 263, 309, 355, 397
barbers - 263, 507
Bartlett, Louis - 654
Bayshore Highway - 309
bee keeper - 163
beer - 507
berry baskets - 217
berry growers - 163
Better America Federation - 217, 286
Bible in public schools - 80, 263
Big Basin - 113, 163, 263, 287, 309
billboards - 28
birds and arbor conservation - 80, 113
blindness - 80
Blue Sky Law - 28, 80, 342
Board of Equalization - 632
bootleg (see also stills) - 382
Boiler inspection - 28
boxing - 263
Briggs, A.H. (State Superintendent of the California Anti-Saloon League). - 440
Briggs, C.R., - 654
Bromley Spoils System bill - 696
budget, State - 217, 264, 266, 267, 309, 357, 461, 513-14
budget, uniform laws for counties - 357
building and loan - 113, 163, 217, 263, 358, 382, 398, 463-64, 515-16, 697
Bureau of Commerce - 516
business colleges - 309
The California Liberator - 190
California Oriental Exclusion League - 188
California Polytechnic School - 276
Cameron, W.H. - 654
capital punishment - 81, 114, 115, 165, 218, 268, 359, 399, 518
Caranhan, H.L. - 165
Catholics - 218, 518
Cattlemen's Association - 218
cement trust - 29, 81, 401-404, 693
cemeteries - 81, 518
cemetery protection - 165, 268
cemetery removal - 218
Central Valley water project - 654
chain stores - 465, 519
Chamber of Commerce - 114, 165, 218, 441, 520, 633, 658
charities and correction - 81, 268
chattel mortgage - 81, 268
Child Hygiene Board - 165
child labor - 114, 165, 268, 310, 359, 633, 698
child welfare - 268, 359
Chile, aid to - 165
chiropractors - 521
Christian Science - 268
civil service - 466
Clear Lake - 165
collection agencies - 218
colleges, at Sacramento - 81
Sec. - 466
Colorado River project - 268
commercial arbitration - 190
commercial federation - 165
Commonwealth Club - 218
community property - 114, 165, 218, 268, 360, 699-700
compensation insurance - 81
comptroller - 218
conservation - 29
constitutional convention - 635
cooperatives - 114, 383
corporation bills - 81
corporation taxes - 165, 268
counties - 218
county clerks - 268
county government - 81, 165, 268, 310, 360, 524
county water district - 524
courts (see also judges) - 268
Cox, James - 190
coyotes - 218
Crail, Joe - 494
Creel, George - 658
crime and criminals (see also capital punishment) - 29, 118, 218, 268, 360
dairy council - 270
dairy laws - 166, 219
daylight savings - 442
deaf and blind - 166, 270, 525
death penalty (see capital punishment) -
deciduous fruit - 219, 361
delinquent women - 166, 270
dental mechanics - 270
district attorneys - 82
divorce - 270
Domestic Court - 270
draft - 124
dredges - 270
dried fruit - 467
drinking cup law - 115
dry candidates - 137
dry zone - 30
Dumbarton bridge - 115
Eberhard, Roy C. - 659
education - 82, 116, 167-69, 219, 270, 311, 362, 468-69, 592-629
Education, State Department of - 561
education investigation committee - 179-187
education, part-time (see also Adult education) - 276
eight hour law - 31, 219
elections (of 1918 - 135-36) - 82, 638-40
Ellis, W.R. - 659
embalmer's bill - 31
employment agencies - 167, 270
Equalization, State Board of - 82
eugenics - 31
exemption, doctors - 311
expert testimony (witnesses) - 116, 167, 219
fair trade - 527
farm labor - 117
farmers - 170, 384
Farmer's Union - 117
farms and farming - 270, 527, 641, 661
Federal aid - 180
Federal practice liens - 270
feed standards - 170, 636
fees, official - 170
ferries - 32
fire boats - 170
firearms - 363
fish and game - 32, 82, 170, 270, 312, 363, 470, 528
fish and game law - 117
food control - 219
foot and mouth disease - 270
forest fire legislation - 182
forestry - 32, 170, 190, 219
forests - 270
fraternities - 32
Free, Arthur, M. - 494
fruit standardization - 483
gambling - 83, 529
gasoline - 219, 271
gasoline tax - 364, 471, 530
German, teaching of in California schools - 171
Givens, Willard E. - 660
Glasson, Maude C. - 660
grade crossings - 364
grand jury - 117, 171
Grange (see also farmers) - 411
Grant, E.E. recall election - 83
Grape Growers' Association - 219
grape growing - 117
Haight, Raymond - 662
Happy Valley Irrigation District - 117
Harding's liquor record - California - 190
Hardy, Judge Carlos S., trial of - 412
Harris bill - 220
hay - 171
Haynes, John Randolph - 662
Haynes, John Randolph foundation - 532
health insurance - 117, 171, 220
Hetch Hetchy - 271
Hichborn, Franklin - 271, 314, 344, 378, 392, 422, 495, 572, 652, 663-64, 739-743
high schools - 220
highway patrol - 533
highways - 220, 271, 365
Hill, Andrew P. - 171
historical association - 533
history textbooks - 271
holding companies - 533
holidays - 533
homesteads - 171
Hoover, Herbert - 190
clippings - 385
horticulture - 220
humane pound - 534-535
Hunter's Point project - 171
hydro-electricity - 220
income tax - 537
indemnity certificates - 221
indeterminate sentence - 221
Indian Basin - 83
Indians - 118
Industrial Accident Commission - 171, 473
industrial strikes - 314
inheritance tax - 365
initiative - 118, 171, 221, 271, 314, 538-41, 642-645, 701
injunction - 34, 83, 171, 314
Inman - 500
installment taxes - 542
Institute of Technology - 229
insurance - 34, 83, 118, 171, 221, 473
I.W.W. - 171
investment trusts - 473
Irish - 271
irrigation - 34, 83, 221, 271
jail - 119
Japanese - 172, 188, 221, 272
immigration - 35, 84
Jews - 221
Jitneys (see automobiles) -
Johnson, Charles G. - 665
Johnson, Hiram - 119, 190, 286, 356, 398
Jones, H.C., bills - 80, 113, 164, 263, 508
Jones, H.C., election campaigns - 1912 - 2a
Jones, H.C., election campaigns - 1914 - 49-52
Jones, H.C., election campaigns - 1926 and 1090 - 339-341
Jones, H.C., election campaigns - 1930 - 443-447
Jones, H.C., election campaigns - 1933 - 654
Jones, H.C., speech - 572
judges - appointment of - 84, 172, 221, 366, 413, 474, 546, 703
Judiciary Committee - 84, 366, 414-417, 704-709
Judiciary reform - 35
jury system - 84, 119, 272, 314
justice of the peace -
juvenile court - 84, 119
kindergarten legislation - 272, 601-606
King tax bill - 272
Klu Klux Klan - 272
Kosher - 367
labor - 36, 85, 120, 165, 188, 222, 272, 367, 418, 548
labor legislation and labor record of legislature - 272, 736
Lake County land settlement - 222
land settlement act - 120
Lawyer's bill, - 710
legal reform - 120, 165
League of Nations - 165
League of Women Voters - 314
Lick Observatory - 85
liquor - 36, 85, 120
loan sharks - 85
lobbying - 272
Loma Prieta Game Refuge - 272
lotteries - 272
McPherson, Aimee Semple - 412
manufacturers - 223
market act - 86, 121, 173
marketing price - 223
Marshall Plan - 223
masks, safety - 273
maternity - 273
Matton act - 551
Meadow Larks - 173
mechanic's lien law - 37
mediation - 121
medical - 38, 86, 121, 173, 223, 273, 477
Merriam, Frank - 668
military training (1917) - 122
military training (1917) in schools - 121, 173, 223
milk bill - 173, 477
minimum wage law - 36, 273
Mooney case - 173, 1077
morons - 121
mortgage and loan - 315
Mother lode mine - 273
mother's pension - 121
motion pictures - 223, 273
motor carriers - 712
motor vehicles (taxation of, 274) - 173, 223, 315, 552
Muir, John, trail - 86
music teachers - 477
mutual insurance - 368
narcotics - 419, 1079
hospital - 553
National Guard - 224
The National Republican - 226
nautical school - 553
Negro - 658
newspapers - 369
non-partisan - 87, 275
Normal schools - 87, 123, 224
nurses - 173, 224, 369
oil - 87, 275
old age pensions - 275-276, 437, 554
oleomargarine - 225, 316
Olson, Cuthbert L. - 715
optometry - 316
osteopaths - 225
Owens Valley Power and Recreation - 715-716
Pacheco Rancho - 174
Pacific Epileptic Colony - 276
paint - 174
Palo Alto annexatio - 370
Parent-Teachers in schools - 124
Parks and Park Commission - 88, 316, 370, 557, 717
partisanship (see also non-partisan) - 276
peace - 40, 174
pension; for teachers - 40
(pension; for widows - 88) - 124, 174
pest control - 480
petroleum central - 190
picketing - 276
Pine road - 276
pipe line bill - 40
poet laureate of California - 422, 480, 557
police - 124
political campaigns (1914) - 53
political campaigns (1920-1938) - 720-726
political prisoners - 276
power trusts - 225, 276, 388, 422
primary, direct - 225
primary laws - 174, 557
prison bill (womens) - 422
prison bill (womens) labor - 316
prisons - 124, 225
probate orders - 225
photographs - 174
probate procedure - 174
probation - 124, 276, 480
Progressive Commonwealth Party - 675
Progressive Party, 1
Progressive Voters League - 328-338, 727
Progressives - 225
prohibition - 137, 174, 225, 276, 370, 423, 558, 728-729
proportional representation - 276
prostitution - 225
psychopathic hospital, state - 174
public defenders - 124, 174
public health - 33, 423, 558, 730
public ownership - 40, 223, 558
public utilities - 480, 559
public works - 276, 558
pure food - 225
Quinn, John R., 1039
railroad commission - 263, 277
railroads - 88, 175, 226, 481
railroads, government control - 171
real estate - 124, 226, 277
reapportionment - 226, 278-281, 317, 481
reclamation - 124-129, 175
reconstruction, post World War I - 175
recorders - 175
recreational inquiry committee - 45-48
Red Cross - 175
Redwood League - 175, 226
Redwood Park - 88, 371
referendum (see also initiative) - 642
rehabilitation, industrial - 226
religious education - 371
reporters, court - 371, 226, 317
Republican Party - 277
Republicans - 175
retail license tax - 481
revenue - 277
revolver law - 226, 277
Riley Tax bill - 562
roads and highways - 41, 88, 175, 277, 563
Rolph administration investigation - 544-5, 564, 574
Roosevelt, T. club - 731
Rosecrucians - 732-734
sabotage - 282
San Francisco harbor - 171, 176, 220
San Jose port - 40, 557
Santa Clara boundary - 265
Santa Clara township - 229
school administration - 383
schools - 130, 176, 282, 483, 678-670
schools, county elementary - 409
Seavy, Clyde L. - 680
sewage research - 429
shearer content - 176
short ballot - 89, 130, 176
Sinclair, Upton - 681
Sloane, W. A. - 176
slot machines - 372
social evil - 42
social insurance - 229
social welfare - 567
socialism - 42, 89
Soviet health insurance - 176
spiritualists - 372
spoils system - 282
Spreckels, Rudolph - 685
state fair - 42
state government reorganization - 228
stills - 372
subsidized officials - 282
Sunday Closing law - 42, 130, 176
supervisors, county - 282
supreme court - 372
surety companies - 176
surplus corporation - 282
Sutter Basin - 130
syndicalism, criminal - 229, 317, 373, 567
taxes and taxation - 43, 131, 229-233, 283, 374, 425, 429-433, 485, 497, 523, 566, 569, 650
Tax Commission - 131, 426-428
teachers - 994
agencies - 283
retirement - 561
tenure - 283, 374, 628-629
(pension for - 40, 131;) 90, 163, 486-488
textbooks - 131
tidelands - 177
Tioga Road - 131
title companies - 283, 374
toll bridges - 374
Torrens Land Title Law - 43, 131, 317
trading stamps - 131, 177
trappers - 131
trucks - 570
trusts - 131
tuberculosis - 43, 90, 177, 283, 511
Tulare Lake District - 131
unemployment - 572
uniform condition sales act - 234
University, State, budget, 572
usury - 91
utilities, taxation of - 573
vaccination - 44, 91, 234
VD - 177
veterans - 574
vivisection - 132-133, 177, 234
vocational training - 284
Volstead Act (see also prohibition) - 234, 497
war gardens - 178
war loan organization - 234
war risk insurance - 178
water - 134, 497
water and power - 284
water conservation - 434, 581
water development act - 234
water plan, State - 576-580
water supply - 91
Whitney, Charlotte Anita, case of - 190
Whittier school - 178
women, employment - 476, 551
women's bill - 134
Women's Relief Corp. - 284
women's suffrage - 178
Working Reserve, U.S. Boys - 178
workmen's compensation - 44, 91, 134, 178, 235-236, 284, 318
Young, C. C. - 313, 376, 447-453, 686
Y.M.C.A. - 134
Pamphlet on The Progressive Voters League, 1923-26 in first copy of registers.